Guide to the Ida Shepard Oldroyd Papers
Ida Shepard Oldroyd papers,
1888-1940
M1330
Oldroyd, Ida Shepard.
1 linear ft. (2 manuscript boxes)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Collection contains incoming correspondence, 1888-1940 addressed to Ida Shepard Oldroyd, a curator of Geology at the Stanford University Museum, as well as records of transfers, exchanges and acquisitions of materials for the geology collection from the same time period.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Biography / Administrative History
Ida Shepard Oldroyd was a curator of Geology at the Stanford University Museum. She was born in 1857 and died on July 9, 1940. She was an authority on sea shells, or conchology, and wrote three extensive volumes entitled THE MARINE SHELLS OF THE WEST COAST OF NORTH AMERICA, Stanford University Press, 1924-1927.
Scope and Content of Collection
Collection contains incoming correspondence, 1888-1940 addressed to Ida Shepard Oldroyd, a curator of Geology at the Stanford University Museum, as well as records of transfers, exchanges and acquisitions of materials for the geology collection from the same time period.
Arrangement
Arranged into two series. Series 1, Incoming correspondence, is arranged alphabetically within box 2. Series 2, Records of transfers, exchanges and acquisitions, is filed alphabetically by name of institution in Box 2.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Oldroyd, Ida Shepard.; Conchology.; Science--History.; Shells.; Women in Science.
Collection Contents
- Incoming correspondence, 1888-1940, Series 1
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A, 1918 - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - B, 1909 - 1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - C, 1933 - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - D, 1902 - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - E, 1921 - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - F, 1918 - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - G, 1931 - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - H, 1904 - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - I - J, 1920 - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - K, 1929 - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - L, 1918 - 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - M, 1921 - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - N, 1916 - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - O, 1918 - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - R, 1901 - 1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - S, 1916 - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - T, 1919 - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - V, 1926 - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - W, 1917 - 1935 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - XYZ, 1919 - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Records of Exchanges, Sales & Acquisitions, 1888-1940, Series 2
  - Miscellaneous records, 1918 - 1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - A1, 1916 - 1932 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - A2, 1916 - 1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - C, 1918 - 1936 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - E, 1923 - 1929 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - F, 1916 - 1924 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - G, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - H, 1915 - 1923 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - L, 1918 - 1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - M, 1918 - 1921 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - P, 1926 - 1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - R, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - S, 1918 - 1932 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - T, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - U, 1890 - 1933 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - W, 1918 - 1936 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous invoice & records, 1926 - 1934 (Box 2, Folder 17)